A Guide to the Fulgham-Fulghum Family National Association Records, 1977-2013
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Fulgham-Fulghum Family National Association Records, 1977-2013
The Library of Virginia
50933
8.35 cubic feet (18 boxes).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the Fulgham-Fulghum Family National Association, Jacksonville, Florida.
Historical Information
The Fulgham-Fulghum Family National Association, Inc. was a non-profit educational, historical, and genealogical research society incorporated in the State of Florida. Its mission was to study, research, interpret, and preserve the history and achievements of the Foljambe/Fulgham/Fulghum and related families. The group promoted family interaction, stimulated interest in family history by funding and maintaining active research programs, and supplied historical and genealogical information on the family to interested persons. The Association also stimulated interest in family history and genealogy through reunions with exhibits, programs, workshops, and lectures.
Scope and Content
Records, 1977-2013, of the Fulgham-Fulghum Family National Association, including brochures and guidebooks, clippings, compilations, correspondence, newsletters, obituaries, pedigrees and genealogical charts, photographs, as well as copies and transcriptions of census records, land grants and patents, wills, and published sources. The records of the Association document the Foljambe family in England and the descendants of Capt. Anthony Fulgham (d. 1669) of Isle of Wight County, Virginia, as well as the allied families of Boykin, Dean, Johnson, Lea, Raiford, Sledge, Stokes, Todd, and Wheless.
The bulk of the collection is information collected and compiled by Dr. James Elijah Fulghum (1906-2002). The folders entitled "Letters" and "Records" include correspondence he received from other family members with information on their particular branch. This information was originally kept in numbered three-ring binders. Dr. Fulghum also compiled ten "books" entitled "Fulghum Families," which contain individual sheets for family members throughout the United States. The sheets include the individual's identification number, name, date/place of birth and death, marriage information, burial place, names of children, and other biographical details. There is a full name index filed at the end of "Fulghum Families."
The collection also includes the Association's newsletter "Fulgham-Fulghum Family Facts," a photo album of a trip to England by Dr. Fulghum, and the family Bibles of Charles Mallory Fulghum (1860-1921) and Jesse Fulghum (1779-1844).
Contents List
- Accessions. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Ancestors of James Elijah Fulghum. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Background Information. (Box 1, Folder 3-7)
- Boddie - Isle of Wight County Families. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Bohning 31 August 1919. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- "Boykin: Wilson-Johnson-Wayne-Nash Counties, NC, 1785-1975" by B.J. Bunn, Jr.. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- "Call Me Ivy and More" by Evelyn Fulgham Crow, 1990. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Cape Henry - Vial of Sand. (Box 17, Folder n/a)
- The Cauldron - Mercer University, 1914. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- "Charles Ellis Collection of Genealogies for Fulghum, Ellis, Durant, and Best, 1623-1991" (16 mm microfilm). (Box 17, Folder n/a)
- Charts/Pedigrees/Family Group Sheets. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Chesterfield (England) Parish Church - Cross Repair. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Clippings. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- "Cornelius Jansen Clopper and His Descendants" by John R. Witcraft, 1912. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- "Descendants of William and Mary Bousman Zollman" by Wilbur B. Zollman, 1942. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Ellis, Charles Brantley - Photograph. (Box 18, Folder 1)
- England/North Carolina. (Box 2, Folder 6-7)
- Family Gatherings. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- "The Family Heritage Book". (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Family History Book, 1990. (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Family Tree Maker's Family Archives - Genealogical Records: Early Georgia Settlers, 1700s-1800s (CD #516). (Box 17, Folder n/a)
- Foljambe Armorial Manuscript. (Box 18, Folder 2)
- Foljambe, Colin. (Box 18, Folder 3)
- "The Foljambe Collection Removed From Osberton Hall" (Christie's Auction Catalogue), 2008. (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Foljambe, Sir Godfrey. (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Foljambe, Sir Godfrey - Portrait. (Box 18, Folder 4)
- "From Fulliambe to Fulghum: Captain Anthony Fulghum to James Hooks Fulghum, Sr. and His Extended Family," 2006. (Box 2, Folder 13)
- "Fulghum Families" - Book No. 1 - John and His Descendants. (Box 3, Folder 1-4)
- "Fulghum Families" - Book No. 2. (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
- "Fulghum Families" - Book No. 3 - Michael and His Descendants. (Box 3, Folder 7-9)
- "Fulghum Families" - Book No. 4 - Virginia, Alabama, Mississippi, and Texas. (Box 3, Folder 10-13)
- "Fulghum Families" - Book No. 5 - Tennessee, Indiana, Texas, Georgia, and Florida. (Box 4, Folder 1-4)
- "Fulghum Families" - Book No. 6 - North Carolina, Florida, and Georgia (Dade County). (Box 4, Folder 5-8)
- "Fulghum Families" - Book No. 7. (Box 4, Folder 9-11)
- "Fulghum Families" - Book No. 8. (Box 4, Folder 12-15)
- "Fulghum Families" - Book No. 9. (Box 5, Folder 1-3)
- "Fulghum Families" - Book No. 10. (Box 5, Folder 4-5)
- "Fulghum Families" - Index. (Box 5, Folder 6-7)
- "Fulghum Family Cookbook". (Box 6, Folder 1)
- "Fulghum Family Research Project" - Scope of Work. (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Fulgham, Rev. Philip Obediah. (Box 6, Folder 3)
- "Fulgham-Fulghum Family Facts," nos. 1-73, 1987-2013. (Box 6, Folder 4-11)
- "Fulgham-Fulghum Family Facts," Index to nos. 1- 53. (Box 6, Folder 12-13)
- Fulgham, John (1770-1851). (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Fulgham, Michaell. (Box 6, Folder 15)
- "The Fulghams" by Jill Harwood. (Box 6, Folder 16)
- "The Fulghum and Kindred Families" by James E. Fulghum, 1978. (Box 7, Folder 1)
- "The Fulghum and Kindred Families" by James E. Fulghum (rev.), 1987. (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Fulghum, Charles Mallory - Family Bible. (Box 15, Folder n/a)
- Fulghum, Elizabeth Lee. (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Fulghum, Eugene S. - Family History (CD). (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Fulghum, James Elijah. (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Fulghum, James Hooks. (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Fulghum, Jesse - Family Bible. (Box 16, Folder n/a)
- Fulghum, Jesse F.. (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Fulghum, Joseph Harrison. (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Fulghum, Peter. (Box 7, Folder 9-13)
- Fulghum, Robert Neil. (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Fulghum, Robert Schmidt. (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Fulghum - Rock Ridge and Sims, Wilson County, NC. (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Fulghum Settlements - Wayne and Wilson Counties, NC. (Box 18, Folder 5)
- Genealogical Chart. (Map-case 2, Drawer 11)
- Genealogical Research - Jesus Christ of Latter Day Saints. (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
- Genealogy - Brochures, How-To, etc.. (Box 8, Folder 3-4)
- Georgia Vital Records: Marriages, 1775-1900 Selected Counties (Ancestry.com CD). (Box 17, Folder n/a)
- "The Great Book of Fulghums". (Box 8, Folder 5-9)
- Guidebooks - England. (Box 8, Folder 10-11)
- "The Heiligh and Harley Family" by J.R. Witcraft, 1914. (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Heraldry. (Box 9, Folder 2)
- "The History of the Raiford Family" by William Russell Raiford, 1989. (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Johnson (North Carolina). (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Letters No. 1. (Box 9, Folder 5-6)
- Letters No. 2. (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Letters No. 3. (Box 9, Folder 8-9)
- Letters No. 4. (Box 9, Folder 10-11)
- Letters No. 5. (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Letters No. 6. (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Letters No. 7. (Box 10, Folder 2-3)
- Letters No. 8. (Box 10, Folder 4-5)
- Letters No. 9. (Box 10, Folder 6-7)
- Letters No. 10. (Box 10, Folder 8-9)
- Letters No. 11. (Box 10, Folder 10-11)
- Letters No. 12. (Box 10, Folder 12-13)
- Letters No. 13. (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
- Letters No. 14. (Box 11, Folder 3-4)
- Letters No. 15. (Box 11, Folder 5-7)
- Letters No. 16. (Box 11, Folder 8-9)
- Letters No. 17. (Box 11, Folder 10-11)
- Letters No. 18. (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Letters No. 19. (Box 12, Folder 1-3)
- Letters No. 20. (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Letters No. 26. (Box 12, Folder 5-6)
- Letters No. 28. (Box 12, Folder 7-9)
- Letters No. 31. (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
- Map of Isle of Wight County, Virginia. (Map-case 2, Drawer 11)
- Michael-Osberton. (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous. (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Obituaries/Funeral Programs. (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Photo Album - England Trip by Dr. James E. Fulghum. (Box 13, Folder n/a)
- Records No. 33. (Box 13, Folder 6-7)
- Records No. 33. (Box 14, Folder 1)
- "The Relationship of the Fulghum Family to the Old Brick Church, Historic St. Luke's Church, Isle of Wight County, Virginia," 2007. (Box 14, Folder 2)
- "Todds of the Eastern Shore Maryland" by J.R. Witcraft, 1912. (Box 14, Folder 3)
- "The Virginia Todds" by J.R. Witcraft, 1913. (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Virginia 2007 Community Program/FFFNA - Certificate of Recognition. (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Wheless, Elijah J.. (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Wills. (Box 14, Folder 7-8)
- Wood, Peggy Fulghum. (Box 14, Folder 9)